Chad Coker 206-999-9581 wccoker@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/chadcoker

Summary

Throughout my 10+ years of managing large-scale, multi-faceted projects, collaborating on teams and engaging with personal tech products, I am continually amazed and awestruck by the ability of thoughtfully applied technology to efficiently aid in the solution of complex and important problems. This passion leads me into the next phase of my career, and I am excited to contribute to the positive progression of the tech industry through thoughtfully designed full stack web applications to solve real world problems.

Skills and Qualifications

* Programming Languages:

HTML/CSS, JavaScript, Ruby

* Databases:

PostgreSQL, MongoDB

- * FrameWorks and Technologies: JQuery, ReactJS, Bootstrap, Materialize, NodeJS, Ruby on Rails, Express, EJS, Mongoose, Sequelize, ERB
- * 10+ years' experience project managing cross-divisional, IT and quality assurance-focused initiatives.
- * Strong team building and collaboration experience using Agile and Lean principles.

Experience

Freelance Web Design

November 2017 – Present

* Websites and full stack web apps designed to client specifications and expectations.

Web Development Immersive Course | General Assembly July 2017 – November 2017

- * A twelve week, fully immersive program for full stack web development featuring 400+ hours of instruction, daily deliverables and week-long project sprints following agile principles.
- * Instructed in industry best practices for code syntax, RESTful routing, MERN stacks and Git workflows.
- * Utilized agile principles while working both individually and as part of a team, building full stack web apps from scratch and from existing code.

787 Supplier Management Change Management Lead | The Boeing Company June 2010 – June 2016

- * Promoted from Representative to Lead in January 2015 after demonstrating consistent exceptional project management leadership.
- * Led cross functional teams of 4-30 IT, engineering and supply chain management professionals in managing improvements to the efficiency, performance and regulatory compliance of the Boeing 787 Dreamliner, an aircraft comprised of 2.3 million parts and complex, integrated systems.
- * Trained new and existing team members on change management processes, utilizing the opportunity to establish trust and rapport with team members and encourage collaboration.
- * Led 90-day onsite project at international partner site to improve finished product quality. Achieved assignment objectives through facilitating change board meetings with integrated teams from the entire supply chain including engineering, quality assurance, manufacturing and sub-tier parts and raw material suppliers. Quality Assurance and Technical Supervisor | Pacific Bag Inc. August 2007 June 2010
- * Supervised a team of four quality technicians and rotating temporary staff for Pacific Bag's west coast quality control laboratory responsible for testing every flexible packaging component offered by the company.
- * Performed quality investigations and root cause analyses on any incoming product not meeting the quality standard. Provided detailed control solutions to the supplier and written synopsis to the impacted customer.
- * Directed packaging engineering projects in collaboration with sales and marketing teams to ensure the package met all the technical specifications, regulatory and marketing needs of the customer.

Education

General Assembly | Seattle, Washington

July 2017 – November 2017

Web Development Immersive

University of North Dakota | Grand Forks, North Dakota

August 1998 – December 2003

Bachelor of Science in Business Administration and Airport Management.

Coker |